<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gov 1347 - 2022 Midterm Elections Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gov 1347 - 2022 Midterm Elections Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Post Election Model Reflection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-11-19-post-election-model-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-11-19-post-election-model-reflection/</guid>
      <description>After a long semester of model making and an even longer campaign season, the midterm elections are finally in the rearview. To the surprise of many, no red wave came despite an increasingly dire media narrative and tightening polls in the days leading up to the midterm elections. While final vote tallies are still being counted we have a good enough idea of where the final tally stands. As of November 22nd, Democrats have held the Senate and await a Runoff election in Georgia to determine if they will expand their slim majority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Midterm Election Model</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-11-07-final-midterm-election-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-11-07-final-midterm-election-model/</guid>
      <description>#Overview
Hi All! After several weeks of experimenting reworking and shifting the election is upon us meaning this is my final prediction. In the end, I have focused on a national vote share model and a resulting seat share model based on this prediction. My final prediction outlined in more detail below, predicts that Republicans will win 226 seats while Democrats will win 209. While I feel confident that the predicted seat distribution is in the right range, I was unable to fully solve issues of data limitations that we have been facing all semester which means that the confidence interval on this prediction is very large, with over a 10 seat swing in either direction predicted as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Election Forecast</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-11-05-final-election-forecast/test_pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-11-05-final-election-forecast/test_pdf/</guid>
      <description>#Overview
Hi All! After several weeks of experimenting reworking and shifting the election is upon us meaning this is my final prediction. In the end, I have focused on a national vote share model and a resulting seat share model based on this prediction. My final prediction outlined in more detail below, predicts that Republicans will win 226 seats while Democrats will win 209. While I feel confident that the predicted seat distribution is in the right range, I was unable to fully solve issues of data limitations that we have been facing all semester which means that the confidence interval on this prediction is very large, with over a 10 seat swing in either direction predicted as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog 7</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-10-25-blog-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-10-25-blog-7/</guid>
      <description>This week we looked at shocks and unexpected events in elections. Shocks are inherently difficult to operationalize and incorporate into models because their nature is that they produce one off events with no clear data to train a model on. The literature looking at shocks has produced an inconclusive lack of consensus. Some studies show even large shocks don’t produce lasting impacts on voter opinion. Others show that even shocks unrelated to politics such as Shark attacks or natural disasters can impact voter behavior (Achen and Bartels).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog 6: Turnout</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-10-10-blog-6-turnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-10-10-blog-6-turnout/</guid>
      <description>This week in election analytics we examined the impact of voter turnout on election outcomes. Historically, increases in voter turnout have been thought to benefit Democrats. However, in the post-Trump Republican party, this relationship has been called into question. In the Post-Trump era, Republicans have tapped into a new base, largely non-college educated white males, who are non-reliable voters (unlike their traditional base of wealthy whites and the elderly, who vote reliably).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog 5 Post</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-10-11-blog-5-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-10-11-blog-5-post/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week we transitioned away from studying “The Fundamentals” of elections and turned to focus more precisely on studying campaigns themselves. We began our exploration of campaign outreach by examining the impact of ads in shaping election outcomes.
Blog Extension: Ad Spending in 2018
I first visualized the ad data in order to look at when campaigns spend on ads. From the 2012, 2014, 2016 and 2018 data it becomes clear that ads spending really begins to pick up in October and continues to increase through election day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 4</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-10-03-blog-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-10-03-blog-post-4/</guid>
      <description>This week’s blog aims to look at the accuracy of expert ratings and how they can be incorporated into our model. I also begin modeling at the district level as opposed to the national models I have worked on over the last three weeks.
I began by mapping the Democratic vote share in the 2018 midterm election cycle at the district level.
## | | | 0% | | | 1% | |= | 1% | |= | 2% | |== | 3% | |=== | 4% | |===== | 8% | |====== | 9% | |========= | 13% | |============ | 17% | |============= | 19% | |============== | 20% | |============== | 21% | |================= | 25% | |================== | 26% | |==================== | 29% | |===================== | 29% | |===================== | 30% | |===================== | 31% | |====================== | 31% | |====================== | 32% | |======================= | 32% | |======================= | 33% | |======================== | 34% | |======================== | 35% | |========================= | 35% | |========================= | 36% | |========================== | 38% | |=========================== | 38% | |=========================== | 39% | |============================ | 40% | |============================ | 41% | |============================= | 41% | |============================= | 42% | |================================ | 46% | |=================================== | 50% | |===================================== | 54% | |======================================== | 58% | |=========================================== | 62% | |============================================== | 66% | |================================================= | 70% | |=================================================== | 74% | |====================================================== | 78% | |========================================================= | 82% | |========================================================== | 82% | |========================================================== | 83% | |============================================================= | 87% | |================================================================ | 91% | |================================================================== | 95% | |===================================================================== | 99% | |======================================================================| 100% I then mapped expert prediction at the district level where the range of ratings (Safe R, Likely R, Lean R, Toss Up, Lean D, Likely D, Safe D) corresponds to a value 1-7 with 1 being a safe Democratic seat and 7 being a safe Republican seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 3 - Polling</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-09-27-blog-post-3-polling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-09-27-blog-post-3-polling/</guid>
      <description>Using Polling to Inform Election Forecasts
Last week, I built a model for the 2022 midterm elections based on the historical relationship between change in Real Disposable Income and election outcome (either Popular Vote Share or Seat Share). While that model was far from perfect and exhibited a great degree of uncertainty, by limiting the data to midterm yebuiars only, I was able to raise the r-squared value to 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 2: Economic Indicators</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-09-15-blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-09-15-blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>Electoral Predictions and forecasts often cite the “political environment” that a given election cycle is taking place in. For example, pundits could cite a growing economy as cause for a good environment for incumbents while troubling foreign policy incidents might add to a bad environment for incumbents. These “fundamentals” exist outside the campaign’s control and set the stage for a given election cycle. But, how accurately can we predict elections with these conditions alone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-09-14-blog-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-09-14-blog-post-1/</guid>
      <description>This blog is being completed as part of GOV 1347: Election Analytics, a course at Harvard College taught by Professor Ryan Enos. It will be updated weekly and culminate in a predictive model of the 2022 midterm elections.
In this first blog post, I aim to familiarize myself with tidyverse and github through an exploration of popular vote margins and seat share margins during the 2018 midterm election cycle. I then explore what these visualizations reveal about Gerrymandering across the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog 6</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2022-10-21-blog-6/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2022-10-21-blog-6/untitled/</guid>
      <description>To begin looking at the relationship between party vote share and turnout, I graphed regressions of both the republican or democrat party vote share on turnout. The graph can be seen below. As pictured, the republican party vote share has a slight negative correlation with turnout while the democrat party vote share has a slight positive correlation with turnout. While the impact doesn’t seem incredibly significant, it seems that greater turnout is a benefit for the democratic party historically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
